Mohmad Idrish Sorathiya

Associate Architect - Mobile

Address Vadodara, India 390020

Phone 919824691948

E-mail idrish2021@gmail.com

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/idrish-

sorathiya-02295

Results-oriented, resourceful and problem-solving software engineer professional. Specializing in large scale software design and development for a wide variety of companies. High level of involvement in the advancement of the industry and adherence to best practice.

Having 12+ Years of experience in Native iOS, Flutter, Xamarin, Firebase and excellent learning skills for adapting new technologies.

Work History

2022-04 - Current

Associate Architect - Mobile

Rishabh Software, Vadodara, India

- Present optimal technical solutions to prospects, prepare detailed effort estimates, and collaborate with sales and project teams to ensure alignment and competitiveness of proposed solutions.
- Define overall architecture of mobile applications, ensuring scalability, performance, and security.
- Evaluate and select appropriate technologies, frameworks, and platforms for mobile development.
- Provide technical guidance and mentorship to mobile development teams.
- Conduct code reviews to ensure adherence to architectural standards and best practices.
- Define API contracts and data formats for seamless communication between mobile clients and server-side components.
- Development of complex modules and help in boostraping project's base structure.

2019-04 - 2022-03

Technical Lead

Rishabh Software Pvt Ltd

- Aliasing with product management for requirement understanding.
- Developing features for mobile app as well as writing cloud functions to serve as lightweight web services.
- Review source code of other developers.
- Managing system deliveries written shell script to deploy web app and using CodeMagic CD tools for mobile app deployments.

- Suggesting enhancements in product features and improvements in code base quality.
- · Created coding guidelines and define best practices.
- Giving training to teammates on different topics like how to write clean code, define resilient architecture etc.
- Taken initiative of starting Xamarin and Flutter technology in mobile department.

2016-04 - 2019-03

Team Leader

Rishabh software Pvt Ltd

- Worked closely with Presales team to identify feasibility, create scope of requirements and provide estimates.
- Reviewed UI design and identify functional gaps or help team in making it easier.
- Defined high level of technical design for projects.
- Help PM in creating sprint plan.
- Implemented most complicated features of apps.
- Track project and keep all stack holders up to date about progress.
- Mentored and guided employees to foster proper completion of assigned tasks.
- Helped teammates in troubleshooting issues.

2012-04 - 2016-03

Senior Software Engineer

Rishabh Software Pvt Ltd

- Defined high level technical design for projects.
- Developed complex features of projects.
- Supervised teammates and help them in achieving their goals.
- Troubleshooted and improved complicated problems of time and memory performance of apps.
- Took responsibility for delivery apps from requirements to store release.

2010-05 - 2012-04

Software Engineer

Moon Technolabs Pvt Ltd

- Adhered to provided UI design and created pixel perfect apps.
- Adhered to provided coding guidelines and wrote highly maintainable solid code for all apps.
- Released apps on Apple Store.

Education

2006-07 - 2010-04

Bachelor of Engineering: Information Technology

Lukhdhirji Engineering College - Morbi

Certifications

Flutter & Dart - The Complete Guide [2020 Edition]

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate

Xamarin Forms: Build Native Cross-platform Apps with C#

Skills

- Native iOS: Since 2010 started carrier as iOS developer.
- Flutter [Bloc, Provider, Clean architecture] Five big apps developed
- Xamarin Classic
- MAUI
- SQLite
- BLE Integrations
 - iHealth Devices like Thermometer(PT3SBT), Blood Pressure Machine(550BT), Oximeter(PO3)
 - Operate custom devices like a Beer cleaning machine, disinfection machine etc.
- NodeJs Created REST APIs
- Firebase
- Git and workflows
- Scrum Framework